FANG LIU

Software Developer

1A CORFE STREET, ILAM, CHRISTCHURCH Fionalion731@gmail.com 0223950386

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am a programmer with team leader experience for a couple of years, and my most programming experience with JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, Web Service, C#, VB6 and MS SQL Server. My preferred role is a software engineer in an enterprising company where I can further my skills and grow together.

EDUCATION

2014 to 2015

Graduate Diploma in Information and Communication Technologies CHRISTCHURCH POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

1996 to 2000

Bachelor in Computer SoftwareBEIJING UNIVERSITY OF
TECHNOLOGY

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Microsoft Visual Studio 2015/2013/2008 With C#, Kendo UI, HTML5, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, Web Service, Cordova, VB6, JAVA, Android.

Microsoft SQL Server 2012/2008R2/2005 with T-SQL and certain DBA skills, Source Control, Crystal Reports.

Experienced with Operation Systems, Networking and IT Support as well, know well Cloud Service and features in AWS.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jul 2015 - Now

ASSURA SOFTWARE

.NET Developer

I am taking .NET developer position which is to:

- Create technical specifications and estimation for the project.
- Design, develop for Assura application and other projects.
- Meanwhile provide technical support to the team of Implementation Consultants.

And I am using the following skills to achieve the projects successfully.

- IIS, ASP/ASP .Net, C# with object orientated programming, design patterns and development methodologies.
- HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, and some JavaScript frameworks like angular js.
- Microsoft SQL 2005-2012 and Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services.
- Manage the source code with Team Foundation Server.

Apr 2015 – Jul 2015

VCARE INTERNATIONAL LIMITEDMobile Application Developer(Part Time)

I took my graduate project in VCare for Sales Mobile Application which uses a JSON web service to read and write user data from Jade database.

- My responsibility is to analysis, design and develop VCare Mobile Sales Application, which uses JavaScript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, JSON.
- The project uses Kendo framework and Cordova library and based on MVC for the main structure. Meanwhile, I use OOP, refactoring and design pattern to improve my source code as it needs. Moreover, I applied some solution to enhance the UI and UX, which is pretty satisfied by sponsors.

KEY SKILLS

Enthusiasm and Responsible for

what I do: Have worked for IT Industry since graduation because completely interested and enjoy what I do.

Strong coordination and troubleshooting skills: Be well organized to address with multi-task. Have strong capability with problem finding and set up sensible solution.

Good communication: Always positively, genuinely communicate with people, and be trusted not only by technical ability but personality.

REFEREES

Mr. Nadun Perera

Assura Software +64221239584

Mr. Hou Xue Wei

Beijing Harmony Shipping & forwarding houxuewei@harmony.com.cn

 SCRUM is used to manage the whole development; I joined the weekly and daily stand-up meeting with other team members. My communication skill is highly commended.

Jan 2007 – Aug 2013

BEIJING HARMONY SHIPPING & FORWARDING CO.,LTD

IT Department Manager

As an IT Manager, I constantly took the challenges of drive the business target. Keep going to use IT technologies, which are combined with business development and innovation, proactively and greatly improved work efficiency and cost reduction.

- Successfully designed and implemented ERP and CRM for five branches; Meanwhile standardized and optimized the data infrastructure in order establisheda unitized system platform.
- I took responsibilities to analysis, designed and implemented the business system, using C# and MS SQL Server to developed the back-end features, also including JavaScript, HTML, CSS to support front-end.
- Recruited professional and skillful IT team of seven people, and motivated them through performance evaluation and rewards and penalties system to work effectively.

Oct 2004 - Dec 2006

BEIJING HARMONY SHIPPING & FORWARDING CO.,LTD

Software Developer

- Successfully constituted and implemented ERP and CRM in headquarters that met and improved the rapid development of business.
- Upgraded from SQL SERVER 2000 to SQL SERVER 2005, and optimized the performance of database.

Jul 2000 - Sep 2004

BEIJING TANGENT ENGINEERING SOFTWARE CO.,LTD

VB Developer

Successfully participated and accomplished project for WMS.